# **April Dockery**

# Front-End Developer with Digital Marketing Experience | Specializing in Shopify Development

Stone Mountain, GA 30087 dockeryapril@gmail.com

Critical thinker and problem-solver (sometimes superb Googler), with over 6 years of graphic design, branding and marketing experience including print work, web design, creating social media content, publishing targeted ads and utilizing technologies such as Adobe Creative Suite, Mailchimp, Klaviyo, Google Ads, Shopify and Salesforce Marketing Cloud. With just over a year of working on web and software development projects, I am looking to join a tech company where there is room for growth and I can utilize my skills and gain some new ones while expressing my creativity.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

# Work Experience

#### **Shopify Developer**

OUDIENCE branding co. - Grand Rapids, MI April 2015 to Present

Build and develop ecommerce brands and digital marketing and advertising strategies, exclusively, on the Shopify platform.

- Consult with clients and verify niche/product ideas
- Develop targeted branding and marketing efforts by researching and analyzing audience demographics, interests, preferences and engagement
- · Website build and development
- Execute A/B testing with Google Ads
- Implement SEO best practices to optimize website pages

# **Communications Campaign Coordinator**

Xtend, Inc. - Grand Rapids, MI January 2020 to August 2020

Handle multi-channel marketing projects for a network of credit unions nationwide.

- Recommend, develop and implement product launches
- Coordinate, support and maintain current communications digitally and in print
- Manage multi-channel marketing campaigns
- Gather and understand data to gain insight into the finance industry
- · Develop reports to guide credit union marketing efforts and increase loan revenue

#### **Uber Driver**

Uber - Grand Rapids, MI August 2017 to August 2018

Transport yummies from local restaurants to Uber Eats customers.

#### **Lifestyle Photographer**

Shutterstock Custom - Grand Rapids, MI December 2015 to June 2018

Shoot stunning branded photo content for the world's top brands for use in marketing campaigns and branding collateral.

- Executed brand requirements by utilizing creative briefs
- Strategically organized and arranged lighting, props and environment to create aesthetic and engaging photographs
- Ensured quality of images using Adobe Bridge and Photoshop
- Digital (DSLR) camera operation

#### **Art Instructor**

Freelance - Grand Rapids, MI January 2010 to December 2015

Facilitate one-on-one and group art classes for school-aged children.

#### Education

# Associate in Multi-Age Education (Art Emphasis)

Owens Community College - Perrysburg, OH 2009

#### **Diploma**

Central High School - Grand Rapids, MI 2002

# Skills

- Digital Photography
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Indesign
- Adobe Illustrator
- Illustration
- · Microsoft Office
- Adobe Acrobat
- · Social Media Monitoring
- Ecommerce Branding
- Graphic Design
- · Digital Marketing
- Search Engine Optimization (SEO)
- MailChimp
- Google Analytics
- Google Ads

- · Email Marketing
- Multichannel Marketing
- PPC Campaign Management
- A/B Testing
- Content Management Systems
- Marketing Automation
- Salesforce
- Project management
- Adobe Creative Suite
- · CRM software
- Marketing

#### Links

https://www.behance.net/aprildockery

https://www.linkedin.com/in/april-dockery-214a8159/

### Certifications and Licenses

#### **Google Ads Search Certification**

January 2020 to January 2021

#### **Google Ads Display Certification**

January 2020 to January 2021

#### **Google Ads Video Certification**

February 2020 to February 2021

# **Google Shopping Ads Certification**

February 2020 to February 2021

#### Assessments

# Social Media — Expert

January 2020

Creating content, communicating online, and building a brand's reputation.

Full results: Expert

# Search Engine Optimization — Highly Proficient

January 2020

Interpreting online website performance metrics and understanding search engine optimization tactics Full results: <u>Highly Proficient</u>

Work Style: Reliability — Highly Proficient

April 2019

Measures a candidate's tendency to be dependable and come to work.

Full results: Highly Proficient

#### Marketing — Expert

October 2020

Understanding a target audience and how to best communicate with them

Full results: Expert

# **Brand Ambassador — Highly Proficient**

December 2020

Promoting brand awareness and sales

Full results: Highly Proficient

#### Market Research — Proficient

December 2020

Analyzing data and using market research tools

Full results: Proficient

#### Attention to Detail — Proficient

September 2020

Identifying differences in materials, following instructions, and detecting details among distracting

information

Full results: Proficient

# **Social Media — Proficient**

November 2020

Knowledge of popular social media platforms, features, and functions

Full results: Proficient

#### **Verbal Communication — Proficient**

September 2020

Speaking clearly, correctly, and concisely

Full results: Proficient

#### Written Communication — Proficient

December 2020

Best practices for writing, including grammar, style, clarity, and brevity

Full results: Proficient

#### **Graphic Design — Proficient**

September 2020

Using graphic design techniques and producing visual media to communicate concepts

Full results: Proficient

# **Customer focus & orientation — Highly Proficient**

December 2020

# Responding to customer situations with sensitivity

Full results: <u>Highly Proficient</u>

Indeed Assessments provides skills tests that are not indicative of a license or certification, or continued development in any professional field.